Paul Mortamet, Applied Mathematics student

Paris, France | paul.mortamet@polytechnique.edu | +33 6 95 09 09 77

PROFILE

Born in Mexico, I grew up in the French countryside (Gers) before successfully entering Ecole Polytechnique in 2019. I am now a 3rd Year student specializing in **Applied Mathematics and Computer Science**. This strong scientific basis brought me to move toward **Artificial Intelligence** by learning its **cognitive** inspirations, optimizing with **Mathematics** and creating with **Machine Learning**.

EXPERIENCE

Sept. 2021 - Dec. 2021

Research Project, LIMSI, Paris (France)

supervized by François Yvon

After going through numerous papers, I created my own solution for the word alignment problem called **Optimal Transport for Cross-lingual Word Alignments.**

- Optimal Transport
- FastText
- Wasserstein GAN & EMDOT
- · Cross-lingual natural language processing

Jun. 2021 - Aug. 2021

AI Research Intern, Fujitsu, Tokyo (Japan)

<u>Internship subject to NDA</u>, few informations available. Developed numerous models, losses and metrics with great results. During this incredibly rich experience I worked on **state of the art research** at the **crossroads of Computer Vision and NLP** on a subject close to **Vid2Text**:

- Optical-Flow
- Encoder-Decoder
- Attention methods
- Pose estimation
- Temporal Convolutional Networks
- Transformers

Sept. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Research Project, MBDA, France

Designing a surveillance system against drone attacks based on drone networks. This experience taught me to think out of the box by finding new solutions: I applied research on wolves behavior to the project.

- 5000+ lines of codes in Java, C++, Python
- A*, RRT*, Genetic Algorithms

EDUCATION

Sept. 2019 - Aug. 2022

Ecole Polytechnique, Paris (France)

Top 1 scientific university in France and one of the best in Europe. Specializing in Applied Mathematics and Computer Science.

Sept. 2017 - Jul. 2019

Lycée Pierre de Fermat, Toulouse (France)

Top 10 French "classes preparatoires" two years of intense scientific classes (around 17 hours of work a day). Participated to the **International Chemistry Olympiad (IChO)** preparation for the French team.

INTERESTS & SKILLS

Fields	Mathematics	Computer Science	Cognitive science	Philosophy
Examples of skills	 Scochastic calculus Optimization Algebra Markov chains Probability	 Algorithmic Data analysis Machine Learning	 Perception Language processing Brain imaging Computational models	FreudHayekPlatoJankelevitchTocqueville
Examples of interests	Solving Optimization problems under Orthogonal constraints in C++		Comparing word embedding and computer vision models to MRI data during visual word recognition	

Kaggle competitions

Google Brain: Ventilator pressure prediction

BNP Paribas Data Challenge

Generative Modelling for Financial Losses